Neri Esparza

Profile

I am a UI Engineer based in NYC with work experience in web advertising, A/B testing & retail e-commerce. I graduated with a bachelor's degree in Computer Science. I am passionate about creating beautiful websites and trying new technologies. Challenging projects are my motivation.

Skills

Programming: HTML, CSS, JavaScript,

JQuery, PHP, SASS

Frameworks: Bootstrap, Symfony,

Codeignter

Learning JS Frameworks: Vue.js,

React.js, Angular.js

CMS: WordPress, Joomla, Adobe CQ,

Oracle Endeca

Tools: Git, Grunt, Gulp, SVN, MySQL.

Education

Universidad Tecnologica de Coahuila -Saltillo, Mexico

Bachelor in Computer Science - 2009 - 2011

IEPSC - Namur, Belgium

Webmaster - 2008 - 2009

Université Paul Sabatier Toulouse III

- Toulouse, France

Networks Security & Systems - 2006 - 2007

Universidad Tecnológica de Coahuila -Saltillo, Mexico

Telematics - 2003 - 2005

Experience

UI Engineer at Barnes & Noble - 2016-2018

- Retail e-commerce experience.
- Daily updates of content via Endeca & Adobe CQ Experience Manager.
- Creation of CQ modules & landing pages in HTML, CSS/ SASS & JavaScript.
- Migration of desktop site to mobile with Bootstrap framework.

UI/UX Engineer at Animus Rex - 2015-2016

- Improved UX interface in house CMS.
- Created style guides and prototypes.
- Hand coded HTML, CSS & JavaScript websites for several clients.
- Implemented responsive optimization in Bootstrap framework.

UI Engineer at Kameleoon Paris - 2013-2014

- Created A/B testing scripts in JavaScript and jQuery using the in house tool to deliver to the final user.
- Implemented responsive optimization in Bootstrap framework. Developed custom Wordpress templates.

UI Engineer Shiva Com Paris - 2011-2013

- Coded HTML, CSS & JavaScript websites for several clients.
- Implemented responsive optimization with media queries.
- PHP development with Symfony framework.
- Email coding.
- Developed custom Wordpress templates.

UI Engineer Grupo W Mexico - 2010-2011

 Hand coded HTML, CSS, JavaScript websites for several clients.